ACTWU's International Affairs Department Records 5619/032
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACTWU's International Affairs Department Records
1976-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. International Affairs Department
Art Gundersheim
5619/032
7 cubic feet
7 linear feet
Correspondence, reports, publications.
This collection consists of correspondence, reports, and files from the office of Art Gundersheim, Director of the International Affairs Department for the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. Included are files on Footwear, the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), Imports, the Labor-Industry Coalition for International Trade (LICIT), Leather Apparel, Multifiber Arrangement (MFA), and Multilateral Trade Negotiations.
6826767
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 08, 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, July 2010
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related collections: 5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America 5619/032 PUBS: ACTWU's International Affairs Department Publications And all other 5619 collections.
Textile industry--New York (State)--New York; Textile workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; Clothing trade--New York (State)--New York; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Gundersheim, Arthur; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Archives.; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. International Affairs Department --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees --Archives; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives
6826767
- Anti-Dumping, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles 20-82 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AVTEX Fibers Dumping Suit, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Business Cards. Domestic. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Business Cards. Foreign. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Codes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Congress (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Consumer Prices (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cornwall, PA. Education Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Department of Labor. Memoranda. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Domestic International Sales Corporation (DISC), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Early Submissions by the Textile Workers Union of America, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Economics. General. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Enterprise Zones, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- European Economic Community (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Exports (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Foreign Industrial Policies and the Future of American Industry (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gloves. Peoples Republic of China., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Art Gundersheim. Meeting Notes., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Art Gundersheim. "To Do" Folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Holland Tariff Bill (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Import Limitation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Industry and Trade Administration. Textile Agreement Performance Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Item 807, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- J.T.R. Program, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Legislation (Box 1, Folder 27)
- N.Y. Citizens for Balanced Transportation, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Organizing, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Political Action Committees, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Press Conference, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Elizabeth Smith. Schedule., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Elizabeth Smith. Schedule., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Elizabeth Smith. Travel, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Table 21 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Trade Adjustment Assistance, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Transshipments (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Textile Apparel Imports Steering Group, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Textile Information Management System. Description and Specification. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- White Paper, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Wool Suit Imports (Box 1, Folder 41)
- ACWA. Data Update. Vol. I, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  pp. 11-608
- ACWA. Data Update Vol.1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  pp.609-831
- ACWA Data Update Vol.1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  pp.832-1044
- ACWA Data Update Vol.2, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  pp.1045- 1180
- ACWA Data Update Vol.2, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  pp. 1181-1315
- ACWA Data Update Vol.2, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  pp. 1316-1462 with two additional attachments
- ACTWU Legislative List, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  95th
- ACTWU SIC 22. 23 Vol.1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Tabs A-C
- ACTWU SIC 22. 23 Vol.1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Tab D pp. 444-678
- ACTWU SIC 22.23 Vol.1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Tab D pp. 679-895
- ACTWU SIC 22.23 Vol.3, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Tabs E - H
- ACTWU SIC 22.23 Vol.3, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Tabs I-K
- AFL-CIO Israel Visit, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- AFL- CIO. Reagan Recession, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  May 26th pp. 1-5
- AFL- CIO Standing Committees, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- AFL- CIO Statements, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  February 19- March 8th
- AFL- CIO Statements, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  February 18-25th
- Conventions, Resolutions (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Contains texts of an address
- Conventions Resolutions AFI- CIO, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Conventions Resolutions ACTWU, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Conventions ACTWU, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Countervailing Duties, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Countervailing Duty Suits [folder 1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Countervailing Duty Suits [folder 2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Countervailing Duties. U.S. Department of the Treasury, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Customs. French Suits, 1976- 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Customs ITA 2a, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Customs Tariff Schedule (Box 3, Folder 6)
  English and Chinese
- Customs Modernization, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- AFIA Policy Paper on Import Control, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  American Footwear Industries Association
- AFIA Extended Import Relief, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Footwear Clippings, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Consultations with the Philippines, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Footwear Correspondence, 1978- 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Footwear. Extension of Import Relief, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Footwear Fact Sheets, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Footwear. Handwritten Notes (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Footwear Imports, 1978- 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Footwear Imports, 1979- 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Footwear Imports Import Relief Program, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Footwear Imports Summary Tables, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Footwear India Countervailing Duty Brief, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Footwear India Uppers, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Footwear MacNeil/Lehrer Reprint Labor and Protectionism, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Footwear National Affairs Committee, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Footwear Stanley Nehmer Testimony, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Footwear Record of Meeting, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  February 5th
- Footwear. Report on Shoe Negotiations and General Observations, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Footwear. Report on Survey (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Footwear Reports, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Footwear. Shoe Import Crisis, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Footwear Statements of Retail Clerks, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  International Union of ACTWU
- Footwear Statistics, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Clippings and Press Releases, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Footwear. 210 Case ITC Hearing Schedule, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Memoranda and Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Petition for Relief Draft 1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Petition for Relief, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Petitioners' Prehearing Brief Draft, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Petitioners' Responses, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Post-Hearing Brief, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Reports and Statistics (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Pre Hearing Brief, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Press Conference Material, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Footwear. 201 Case. A Public Relations Program for the Footwear Industries of America, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Report, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Footwear. 201 Case. Statements and Testimony, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Footwear. 203 Case. Post Hearing Brief, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Full Employment. Correspondence and Memoranda, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Full Employment. General [folder 1 of 2], 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Full Employment. General [folder 2 of 2], 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP) [folder 1 of 2], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP) [folder2 of 2], 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP). Leather, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP). Leather, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Generalized System of Preferences (GSP). Silk Neckties (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Imports. Exceptions Nomination and Justification. Men's and Boy's Apparel Draft, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Imports. Exceptions Nomination and Justification. Men's and Boys' Apparel Final, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  copy 1
- Imports. Exceptions Nomination and Justification. Men's and Boy's Apparel Final, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  copy 2
- Imports. Exceptions Nomination and Justification. Men's and Boy's Apparel. Final, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  copy 3
- Imports. Press Release. Union seeks higher tariffs, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Imports. Statement. Murray Finley and Jacob Sheinkman, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Imports. Statistics, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Imports. Argentina, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Imports. Brazil, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Imports. Colombia, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Imports. India, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Imports. Korea, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Imports. Malaysia, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Imports. Mexico, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Imports. Pakistan, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Imports. Philippines, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Imports. Singapore, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Imports. Taiwan, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Imports. Thailand, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Imports. Uruguay, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- International Trade Commission. Investigation AA1921-181 Richard T. Schulze. Statements, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- International Trade Commission. Investigation AA1921-181 Maurica H. Winger, Jr. Statement (Box 5, Folder 15)
- International Trade Commission. Investigation AA1921-181 John N. Gregg. Statement, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- International Trade Commission. Investigation AA1921-181 Joseph H. Price. Statement, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- LICIT. Background and Purpose. Draft, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- LICIT. Bill regarding unfair import compensation. Draft, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  October 6-7th
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  October 15th
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  July 22nd
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  April 6th
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  November 29th
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  May 31st
- LICIT. Briefing Book, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  November 28th
- LICIT. Clippings, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- LICIT. Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 28)
- LICIT. Exchange Rates. International Debt and Trade Draft, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- LICIT. EximBank Reauthorization, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- LICIT. Lawrence A. Fox Testimony, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- LICIT. Handwritten Notes, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  June 7th
- LICIT. International Trade. Industrial Policies and the future of American Industry. Draft, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- LICIT. Memoranda (Box 5, Folder 34)
- LICIT. Press Release, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- LICIT. Principals Meeting, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- LICIT. Principals Meeting, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- LICIT. Principals Meeting, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- LICIT. Principals Meeting, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- LICIT. Position papers and Briefings, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  October
- LICIT. The problem of Trade Related Performance Requirements (Box 5, Folder 41)
- LICIT. Proposed Amendments to US Trade Laws Draft, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- LICIT. Recommendations of the Japan- U.S. Work Group on High Technology Industries (Box 5, Folder 43)
- LICIT. Section by Section Analysis of the title E Amendments Draft, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- LICIT. Statement of William Bywater and John D. Ong, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- LICIT. Statement of Douglas D. Danforth and Howard D. Samuel, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- LICIT. Statement of LICIT., 1983 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- LICIT. Statement of Herbert K. Schmitz and Brian Turner, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- LICIT. Statement of Alan W. Wolff, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- LICIT. Report to the Development Committee, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- LICIT. Report on Export Disincentives, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  February
- LICIT. Alan W. Wolff. Revisions of Section 301 Draft, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- LICIT. Trade Reorganization, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- LICIT. Specification for Trade Legislation, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- LICIT. Subcommitee on Trade, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- LICIT. Trade Communications Project, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- LICIT. Trade Policy Roundtable Discussion, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- LICIT. Trade Policy Roundtabe Discussion, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- LICIT. Unfair Trade Practice Draft, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 59)
- Leather Apparel. Brief on Behalf of National Outerwear and Sportswear Association (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Leather Apparel. Clippings (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Leather Apparel. Colombia and Brazil Report, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Leather Apparel. Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Leather Apparel. Equipment Purchases, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Leather Apparel. Trade Policy Staff Committee Brief, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Leather Apparel. Uruguay, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Leather Apparel. Uruguay. International Trade Commission Report, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Multifiber Arrangement (MFA). Steering Committee, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Multifiber Arrangement (MFA). MFA Taskforce Hearing, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Multifiber Arrangement (MFA). Special Taskforce. Appendix, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Agreements, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Agreements (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. AFL-CIO. Analysis and Recommendations, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. American Textile Manufacturers Institute. Maintain existing US textile and apparel tariff, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Apparel Exceptions (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Clippings (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Codes, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Developing Country Issues, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Exemptions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Felt Manufacturers Council. Need to exempt pressed felt (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Foreign, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. GATT, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Implementation, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Industrial Trade and Employment Effects of the MTN (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Knitted Outerwear, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Labor Policy and Labor Sector Advisory Committees, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Labor Policy and Labor Sector Advisory Committee. Geneva Meeting, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Man-Made Fiber Producers. Need to maintain tariffs (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. MTN Negotiating Formula, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Notes (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Report on Tariff Negotiations, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Safeguards and government procurement (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Selected problems in MTN Implementing Legislation (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Senate Floor Action, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Statements. AFL-CIO, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Robert S. Strauss, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Subsidies and Countervailing Duties, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Tariff Reduction, 1977 - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Trade Agreement, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Multilateral Trade Negotiations. Wool Manufacturers Council. Need to maintain tariffs, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Performance Reports. First Year, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Performance Reports. Second Year, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Performance Reports. Third Year, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Performance Reports. Fourth Year, 1976- 1977 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Speeches, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Speeches, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Speeches. Clippings (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Speeches. Imports (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Speeches. Notes (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Speeches. Oak Ridge, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Speeches. Solidarity Day, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Statistics, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Statistics, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Statistics. Handbag Data Book, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Subsidies Group, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Subsidies Group, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Tariffs. Files (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Tariffs. Notes (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Tariffs Rates (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Tariffs. Trade Information Committee, 1964-1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Trade Law. Chances, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)